Inventory of the Center for Civil Society International records
Hoover Institution Archives
Center for Civil Society International records
1948-2008
2009C18
Center for Civil Society International.
117 manuscript boxes (46.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, directories, lists, pamphlets, serial issues, and circulated material, relating to voluntary associations in the former Soviet Union, exchanges and person-to-person contacts, religion, peace movements, human rights, and promotion of democracy and citizenship. Includes many publications collected by the Center. Also includes records of the Center's predecessor organization, the Northwest Regional Office of the World without War Council.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Access to sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material requires at least two weeks advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2009.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
The World Without War Council, a national American private nonprofit organization, was founded in 1958 with the primary goal of promoting alternatives to war, and with subsidiary goals of promoting civic education, international understanding and democratic government. Its regional office in Seattle, Washington, successively titled the World Without War Council of Greater Seattle and the World Without War Council Northwest Regional Office, was the predecessor organization of the Center for Civil Society International.
The Seattle office transformed itself into the Center for Civil Society International in 1992. This act reflected a realization of the profound changes in the international situation following the fall of communist regimes in Eastern Europe and the Soviet Union, the disintegration of the Soviet Union, and the end of the Cold War. The new focus of the Center became promotion of democratic values and civil reconstruction in the newly independent states of the former Soviet Union. It sought to act as a clearinghouse for contacts between non-governmental organizations in the United States and elsewhere interested in providing technical and other assistance in the new states, and grassroots non-governmental organizations in those countries.
M. Holt Ruffin became executive director of the World Without War Council of Greater Seattle in 1984 and remained as executive director of the Center for Civil Society International. The Hoover Institution Archives acquired the records of the Center in 2008.
Scope and Content of Collection
Records of both the Center for Civil Society International and of its predecessors, the World Without War Council of Greater Seattle and World Without War Council Northwest Regional Office, are included. The collection is divided into two series.
The Central Organizational Files series contains filing sequences that transcend specific topics and that reflect the continuing life of the organization throughout its temporal stages. Material within this series is arranged by physical form. Notably it includes chronologically arranged correspondence, predominantly outgoing, and chronologically arranged internal documents of other types, including minutes and memoranda. Governing documents, periodical reports of activities, financial records, and some issuances of the organization and its officials may also be found here.
The Subject File series contains material grouped by topic. The main division within the Subject File is between a General subseries of materials not dealing with specific countries on the one hand, and materials arranged alphabetically by country on the other hand. Correspondence with, and published and unpublished issuances of, a wide range of voluntary and other non-governmental organizations, make up the bulk of the Subject File material. The largest volume of material by geographic region concerns the successor republics to the Soviet Union, especially Russia, Ukraine and the Central Asian states. Economic and political reform, civic education, human rights, health and environmental issues, religion, exchange visits, and telecommunication and person-to-person contacts are among the aspects treated. There is also a considerable volume of earlier material from the 1980s, dealing especially with Central America and the Soviet Union, and including material on peace and disarmament movements, as well as exchange and person-to-person contacts and human rights concerns.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series, Central Organizational Files, and Subject files. The main division within the Subject File is between a General subseries of materials not dealing with specific countries on the one hand, and materials arranged alphabetically by country on the other hand.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Civil rights.; Religion.; Peace.; Democracy.; United States--Relations--Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--Relations--United States.; United States--Relations--Former Soviet republics.; Former Soviet republics--Relations--United States.; United States--Relations--Europe, Eastern.; Europe, Eastern--Relations--United States.; World without War Council.
Collection Contents
- Central Organizational Files, 1955-1998. (Box 1-11)
  Governing documents, minutes, memoranda, other internal documents, correspondence, and issuances of the World Without War Council of Greater Seattle, World Without War Council Northwest Regional Office, and Center for Civil Society International successively, arranged by physical form
  - Articles of incorporation and bylaws (World Without War Council of Greater Seattle), 1966-1983 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Programmatic statements, 1961-1985 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Reports,1972-1982 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Reports,1983-1991 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Financial records, 1968-1991 (Folder 1: 5)
  - American Initiatives Project files, 1983-1984 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Historians Projec files, 1983-1984 (Folder 2: 2)
  - Intern program files, 1988 (Folder 2: 3)
  - Internal documents, including minutes and memoranda, 1962-1995 (Folder 2)
    - 1962-1979 (Folder 2: 4)
    - 1980-1983 (Folder 2: 5)
    - 1984 (Folder 2: 6)
    - 1985 (Folder 2: 7)
    - 1986 (Folder 2: 8)
    - 1987 (Folder 3: 1)
    - 1988 (Folder 3: 2)
    - 1989 (Folder 3: 3)
    - 1990 (Folder 3: 4)
    - 1991 (Folder 3: 5)
    - 1992-1995 (Folder 3: 6)
    - Undated (Folder 3: 7)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1998 (Folder 3)
    - 1984 January-July (Folder 3: 8)
    - 1984 August-December (Folder 3: 9)
    - 1985 (Folder 3: 10)
    - 1986 (Folder 4: 1)
    - 1987 January-May (Folder 4: 2)
    - 1987 June-September (Folder 4: 3)
    - 1987 October-December (Folder 4: 4)
    - 1988 January-April (Folder 5: 1)
    - 1988 May-July (Folder 5: 2)
    - 1988 August-December (Folder 5: 3)
    - 1989 January-May (Folder 5: 4)
    - 1989 June-September (Folder 5: 5)
    - 1989 October-December (Folder 6: 1)
    - 1990 January-June (Folder 6: 2)
    - 1990 July-December (Folder 6: 3)
    - 1991 January-June (Folder 6: 4)
    - 1991 July-December (Folder 6: 5)
    - 1992 January-June (Folder 6: 6)
    - 1992 July-December (Folder 6: 7)
    - 1992, Incoming (Folder 7: 1)
    - 1993 January-April (Folder 7: 2)
    - 1993 May-July (Folder 7: 3)
    - 1993 August-December (Folder 7: 4)
    - 1993, Incoming (Folder 7: 5)
    - 1994 January-May (Folder 7: 6)
    - 1994 June-August (Folder 8: 1)
    - 1994 September-December (Folder 8: 2)
    - 1994, Incoming (Folder 8: 3)
    - 1995 January-May (Folder 8: 4)
    - 1995 June-December (Folder 8: 5)
    - 1995, Incoming (Folder 9: 1)
    - 1996 January-June (Folder 9: 2)
    - 1996 July-December (Folder 9: 3)
    - 1996, Incoming (Folder 9: 4)
    - 1997 (Folder 9: 5)
    - 1998 (Folder 9: 6)
  - Pickus, Robert. Articles as president of the World Without War Council of the United States (Folder 10)
    - 1955-1968 (Folder 10: 1)
    - 1969-1977 (Folder 10: 2)
    - 1978-1989 (Folder 10: 3)
    - Undated (Folder 10: 4)
  - Ruffin, M. Holt. Articles as executive director of the World Without War Council of Greater Seattle, 1985-1987 (Folder 10: 5)
  - Civil Society-East and West (newsletter of the Center for Civil Society International), 1993-1996 (Folder 10: 6)
  - Miscellaneous issuances of the Center for Civil Society International, 1993-1998 (Folder 10: 7)
  - Press coverage, 1971-1990 (Folder 11: 1)
  - Photographs. Unidentified contact sheets, undated (Folder 11: 2)
- Subject File, 1948-2008. (Box 11-117)
  Correspondence, lists, memoranda, conference materials, issuances of numerous non-governmental organizations, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - General. Material not limited to a specific foreign country or region
    - Book donation
      - American Council of Learned Societies, 1993 (Folder 11: 3)
      - Friends of Libraries U.S.A., 1991-1992 (Folder 11: 4)
      - International Book Bank, 1990-1991 (Folder 11: 5)
      - Sabre Foundation, 1991-2002 (Folder 11: 6-7)
    - Charities
      - Brother to Brother International, 1989-1992 (Folder 11: 8)
      - Charity Know How, 1996 (Folder 11: 9)
      - Global Jewish Assistance and Relief Network, 1993-1995 (Folder 11: 10)
      - Goodwill Industries of America, 1991-1995 (Folder 11: 11)
      - International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies, 1994 (Folder 12: 1)
      - U.S. Committee for Refugees, 1986-1988 (Folder 12: 2)
      - United Way International, 1990-1995 (Folder 12: 3)
      - United Way of America, 1991-1996 (Folder 12: 4)
      - Children (Folder 12)
      - Children's Art Bridge, 1997 (Folder 12: 5)
      - Children's Defense Fund, 1992 (Folder 12: 6)
      - Save the Children, 1998 (Folder 12: 7)
    - Civic education
      - General, 1982-2000 (Folder 12: 8)
      - American Federation of Teachers Education for Democracy Project, 1987-1996 (Folder 12: 9)
      - American Foundation for Resistance International, 1987-1993 (Folder 13: 1)
      - Carnegie Endowment Democracy and Rule of Law Project, 1999-2001 (Folder 13: 2)
      - Center for Civic Education, 1991-1992 (Folder 13: 3)
      - Citizens Democracy Corps, 1990-1998 (Folder 13: 4)
      - Citizens Network for Foreign Affairs, 1993-1995 (Folder 13: 5)
      - Civic Education Project, 1992-2001 (Folder 13: 6)
      - Civicus, 1994-1997 (Folder 13: 7, Folder 14: 1-2)
      - Civil Society Project, 1996-1998 (Folder 14: 3)
      - Civitas, 1992-1995 (Folder 14: 4-5)
      - Corresponding Academy on Civil Society, 1994-1995 (Folder 14: 6)
      - Facing History and Ourselves, 1991-1994 (Folder 14: 7)
      - Free Congress Research and Education Foundation, 1987-1995 (Folder 15: 1)
      - Institute for American Values, 1996 (Folder 15: 2)
      - International Center for Democracy, 1997 (Folder 15: 3)
      - International Foundation for Electoral Systems, 1992-1996 (Folder 15: 4)
      - International Republican Institute, 1994 (Folder 15: 5)
      - National Democratic Institute for International Affairs, 1988-1992 (Folder 15: 6)
      - National Endowment for Democracy, 1990-1991 (Folder 15: 7-8)
      - North-South Institute, 1999 (Folder 16: 1)
      - Partners for Democratic Change, 1991-2001 (Folder 16: 2)
      - Crime (Folder 16)
      - General, 1986-1992 (Folder 16: 3)
      - Transnational Crime and Corruption Center, 1999-2000 (Folder 16: 4)
      - Development assistance (Folder 16)
      - Canadian Executive Service Organization, 1994 (Folder 16: 5)
      - Canadian International Development Agency, 1996-1997 (Folder 16: 6)
      - Charities Aid Foundation, 1999 (Folder 16: 7)
      - Chemonics International Inc., 1996 (Folder 16: 8)
      - Co-Op America, 1991-1992 (Folder 16: 9)
      - Cooperative Housing Foundation, 1990-1996 (Folder 16: 10)
      - Counterpart Foundation, 1992-1995 (Folder 16: 11)
      - Crafts Center, 1992 (Folder 16: 12)
      - Fondation de France, 1994 (Folder 16: 13)
      - Future Farmers of America, 1990-1992 (Folder 17: 1)
      - Grassroots Economic Organizing Newsletter, 1993-1994 (Folder 17: 2)
      - Growing Connections, 1990-1992 (Folder 17: 3)
      - Tri Valley Growers, 1995 (Folder 17: 4)
      - Trickle Up Program, 1989-1993 (Folder 17: 5)
      - United Nations Conference on Trade and Development, 2000 (Folder 17: 6)
      - United Nations Development Programme, 1993-2004 (Folder 17: 6-9, Folder 18: 1-2)
      - United Nations Volunteers, 1995 (Folder 18: 3)
      - United States. Agency for International Development, 1997-1998 (Folder 18: 4-5)
      - Volunteers in Technical Assistance, 1990-1993 (Folder 18: 6)
      - Watermark Association of Artisans, 1991 (Folder 18: 7)
      - Winrock International, 1990-1996 (Folder 18: 8)
      - World Bank, 1995-2002 (Folder 19: 1-2)
      - World Learning Inc., 1992-1996 (Folder 19: 3)
      - WorldTeach, 1991-1997 (Folder 19: 4)
    - Disabled living (Folder 19)
      - General, 1994-1998 (Folder 19: 5)
      - Access Exchange International, 1989-2003 (Folder 19: 6)
      - Independent Living Research and Utilization Program, 1991-1995 (Folder 20: 1)
      - Wheeled Mobility Center, 1994 (Folder 20: 2)
      - World Institute on Disability, 1990-1995 (Folder 20: 3)
    - Education
      - General, 1989-1996 (Folder 20: 4)
      - Brigham Young University, 1986 (Folder 20: 5)
      - Council for Basic Education, 1991-1992 (Folder 20: 6)
      - Institute of International Education, 1980-1996 (Folder 20: 7)
    - Environment
      - General, 1978-2003 (Folder 20: 8)
      - Courrier de la Planète, 2001 (Folder 20: 9)
      - Earthstewards Network, 1986-1992 (Folder 20: 10)
      - Ecologia, 1996-1997 (Folder 20: 11)
      - Institute for Sustainable Communities, 1998-2003 (Folder 21: 1)
      - United States Environmental Training Institute, 1994 (Folder 21: 2)
    - Exchanges
      - General, 1984-1990 (Folder 21: 3)
      - Center for Innovative Diplomacy, 1986 (Folder 21: 4)
      - Council for International Exchange of Scholars, 1993 (Folder 21: 5)
      - Council on International Educational Exchange, 1987-1995 (Folder 21: 6)
      - Council on Standards for International Educational Travel, 1991-1992 (Folder 21: 7)
      - Foundation for International Professional Exchange, 1995-2000 (Folder 21: 8)
      - Friendship Force, 1990-1994 (Folder 21: 9)
      - Global Volunteers, 1992-1996 (Folder 21: 10)
      - Heartland International, 1995-2001 (Folder 21: 11)
      - International Research and Exchanges Board, 1984-1998 (Folder 21: 12, Folder 22: 1-3)
      - Liaison Group for International Educational Exchange, 1991 (Folder 22: 4)
      - Project Harmony, 1993-2003 (Folder 22: 5)
      - Seattle City Council, 1982-1986 (Folder 22: 6)
      - Seattle Office of International Affairs, 1986-1987 (Folder 22: 7)
      - Seattle's International Agenda Conference, Seattle, Washington, 1985 (Folder 22: 8)
      - Sister Cities International, 1985-1997 (Folder 23: 1)
      - Walkabout, 1993-1995 (Folder 23: 2)
    - Health
      - American International Health Alliance, 1993-1995 (Folder 23: 3)
      - Anne Larkin Homoeopathic Trust, 1995 (Folder 23: 4)
      - Hesperian Foundation, 1991-1992 (Folder 23: 5)
      - Physicians for Human Rights, 1987-1992 (Folder 23: 6)
      - Planned Parenthood Federation of America, 1990-1997 (Folder 23: 7)
      - Project Hope, 1980-1995 (Folder 23: 8)
      - Teen-Aid, Inc., 1989 (Folder 23: 9)
      - Tulsa Global Alliance, 1992-1995 (Folder 23: 10)
      - Wemos, 1996 (Folder 23: 11)
    - Helsinki Accords
      - General, 1975-1999 (Folder 23: 12)
      - European Network for East-West Dialogue, 1987 (Folder 23: 13)
      - Helsinki Watch, 1982-1990 (Folder 24: 1)
      - International Helsinki Human Rights Committee, 1982 (Folder 24: 2)
      - Resistance International/Internationale de la Résistance, 1984 (Folder 24: 3)
      - United States. Congress. Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe, 1982-1999 (Folder 24: 4-7, Folder 25: 1-4)
      - United States. Dept. of State, 1978-1991 (Folder 25: 5-7)
      - United States violations, 1984-1989 (Folder 25: 8)
    - Human rights
      - General, 1994-2002 (Folder 26: 1)
      - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations Conference on Freedom of Association, Washington, D.C., 1988 (Folder 26: 2)
      - Colby College Oak Human Rights Fellowship, 2000 (Folder 26: 3)
      - Congressional Human Rights Caucus, 1989 (Folder 26: 4)
      - Freedom House, 1985-1999 (Folder 26: 5-6)
      - Human Rights Information and Documentation Systems International, 1997-2003 (Folder 26: 7)
      - Human Rights Internet, 1984-1992 (Folder 26: 8)
      - Human Rights Watch, 1987-1998 (Folder 26: 9)
      - Index on Censorship, 1987-1992 (Folder 26: 10)
      - Institutum Europaeum, 1989-1990 (Folder 26: 11)
      - Minnesota Advocates for Human Rights, 2000 (Folder 27: 1)
      - Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe, undated (Folder 27: 2)
      - PEN, 1987 (Folder 27: 3)
      - Universal Declaration of Human Rights, 1948 (Folder 27: 4)
    - Journalism and broadcasting
      - Committee to Protect Journalists, 1992-1996 (Folder 27: 5)
      - International Center for Community Journalism, 1995 (Folder 27: 6)
      - Internews Network, 1995-2004 (Folder 27: 7)
      - Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, 1984-1998 (Folder 27: 8-9)
      - Satellite Broadcasting and Communications Association, 1991-1992 (Folder 27: 10)
      - United States Information Agency, 1986-1997 (Folder 27: 11, Folder 28: 1-2)
      - World Press Freedom Committee, 1990-1994 (Folder 28: 3)
      - Law
      - Constitutional Rights Foundation, 1984-1995 (Folder 28: 4)
      - George Mason University School of Law, undated (Folder 28: 5)
      - International Center for Not-for-Profit Law, 1993-1998 (Folder 28: 6)
      - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 1994 (Folder 28: 7)
      - National Lawyers Guild, 1980-1982 (Folder 28: 8)
    - Nationalities. Association for the Study of Nationalities, 1996-2000 (Folder 28: 9-10)
    - Nuclear disarmament
      - American Friends of the Hibakusha, 1964 (Folder 29: 1)
      - Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament, 1981 (Folder 29: 2)
      - Disarmament Campaigns, 1984-1986 (Folder 29: 3)
      - Federation of American Scientists, 1991 (Folder 29: 4)
      - Ground Zero Center for Nonviolent Action, 1981-1986 (Folder 29: 5)
      - Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy, 1985 (Folder 29: 6)
      - Nuclear Proliferation Symposium, Seattle, Washington, 1985 (Folder 29: 7)
      - Nuclear Times, 1992 (Folder 29: 8)
      - Nuclear Xchange, 1982-1986 (Folder 29: 9)
    - Peace
      - American Friends Service Committee, 1955-1988 (Folder 30: 1)
      - Campaign for Peace and Democracy, 1988-1994 (Folder 30: 2)
      - Center for War/Peace Studies, 1980-1997 (Folder 30: 3)
      - Conscience and Military Tax Campaign, 1988 (Folder 30: 4)
      - Dunamis, 1984 (Folder 30: 5)
      - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1982-1992 (Folder 30: 6)
      - International Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1980-1989 (Folder 30: 7)
      - International Peace Academy, 1989 (Folder 31: 1)
      - Pacific Peacemaker, 1982-1987 (Folder 31: 2)
      - Peace: A Dream Unfolding, 1986 (Folder 31: 3)
      - Peace Activists East and West, 1986-1988 (Folder 31: 4)
      - Peace Brigades International, 1982 (Folder 31: 5)
      - Peace Fleece, 1986-1987 (Folder 31: 6)
      - Peace Review, 1997 (Folder 31: 7)
      - Ploughshares, 1984-1991 (Folder 31: 8)
      - San Jose peace proposal, 1987 (Folder 31: 9)
      - Sasakawa Peace Foundation, 1994-1995 (Folder 31: 10)
      - Seattle Religious Peace Action Coalition, 1980-1983 (Folder 31: 11)
      - Seattle Nonviolent Action Group, 1985 (Folder 31: 12)
      - Seattle Peace and Freedom Coalition, 1987-1991 (Folder 31: 13)
      - Seattle peace movements, 1978-1990 (Folder 31: 14)
      - Strategic Defense Initiative, 1987 (Folder 31: 15)
      - United States Institute of Peace, 1990-2003 (Folder 31: 16, Folder 32: 1-4)
      - University for Peace/Universidad para la Paz de las Naciones Unidas en Costa Rica, 1985-1986 (Folder 32: 5)
      - Untitled typescript anthology of essays edited by Thompson M. Faller and Loretta Ellen Zimmerman, undated (Folder 33: 1)
      - War Resisters' International, 1987-1996 (Folder : 2)
      - World Peace Council, 1982-1992 (Folder 33: 3-4)
      - World Peace Event, Seattle, Washington, 1986 (Folder 33: 5)
    - Philanthropic and nonprofit organizations
      - General, 1993-1994 (Folder 33: 6)
      - Carnegie Endowment, 2000-2004 (Folder 33: 7)
      - Center for the Study of Philanthropy and Voluntarism, undated (Folder 33: 8)
      - Friends Outside, 1992 (Folder 33: 9)
      - Gorbachev Foundation USA, 1993-1995 (Folder 33: 10)
      - Gray Doves International, 1997-1998 (Folder 33: 11)
      - International Foundation for the Survival and Development of Humanity, 1988-1991 (Folder 34: 1)
      - Northcote Parkinson Fund Civil Courage Prize, 2000-2002 (Folder 34: 2)
      - Rotary International, 1989-1996 (Folder 34: 3)
      - Voluntas, 1990-1993 (Folder 34: 4)
    - Politics and government
      - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai Brith, 1969-1987 (Folder 34: 5)
      - Center for the Study of Popular Culture, 1992-1994 (Folder 34: 6)
      - Civic Federation, 1995-1996 (Folder 34: 7)
      - Claremont Institute for the Study of Statesmanship and Political Philosophy, 1987-1995 (Folder 34: 8)
      - Communist Party, U.S.A., 1988 (Folder 34: 9)
      - Conservative Caucus, undated (Folder 34: 10)
      - Covert Action Information Bulletin, 1987-1989 (Folder 35: 1)
      - Discovery Institute, 1993 (Folder 35: 2)
      - Federalist Society for Law and Public Policy Studies, 1987 (Folder 35: 3)
      - Freedom Socialist Party, 1988 (Folder 35: 4)
      - Heritage Foundation, 1986 (Folder 35: 5)
      - Independence Institute, 1986-1990 (Folder 35: 6)
      - International City and County Management Association, 1991-1992 (Folder 35: 7)
      - Kettering Foundation, 1990 (Folder 35: 8)
      - League of Women Voters, 1985 (Folder 35: 9)
      - Marxist-Leninist Party, 1987 (Folder 35: 10)
      - Project Vote Smart, 1993-1995 (Folder 35: 11)
      - Public Citizen Foundation, 1990-1992 (Folder 35: 12)
      - U.S. English, 1988 (Folder 35: 13)
      - Veritas Foundation, 1964 (Folder 35: 14)
    - Preservation
      - General, 1992 (Folder 35: 15)
      - U.S. Committee/International Council on Monuments and Sites, 1991-1994 (Folder 35: 16)
      - World Monuments Fund, 1991-1996 (Folder 35: 17)
    - Private enterprise
      - Center for International Private Enterprise, 1989-1996 (Folder 35: 18)
      - Council of Better Business Bureaus, 1990-1992 (Folder 35: 19)
      - Foundation for Teaching Economics, 1990-1992 (Folder 36: 1)
      - Global Learning of the Business Enterprise, undated (Folder 36: 2)
    - Religion
      - General, 1966-2000 (Folder 36: 3-4)
      - Christian Action Research and Education (CARE), 1993-1995 (Folder 36: 5)
      - East-West Christian Organizations: A Directory of Western Christian Organizations Working in East Central Europe and the Newly Independent States Formerly Part of the Soviet Union, edited by M. Holt Ruffin and others, 1993 (Folder 36: 6)
      - Foundation for a Christian Civilization, 1980 (Folder 36: 7)